<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><xml>
  <node>
    <title>Fresh Start Supplies</title>
    <essay_see_it>The lack of available school supplies to the lower socioeconomic classes.</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>When you attend a private elementary school you aren.t really aware of the socioeconomic differences in people. Imagine my surprise when upon reaching public school I learned that not all kids have the money for basic school supplies, let alone the extras like locker shelves that I got every year.
  The teachers try to help, they save things like gently used binders and purchase extra paper to hand out but on a teacher.s salary with no resources they can.t do all that much despite their best efforts. It seems to get worse as we get older- after all what 15 year old wants to carry around a binder that is obviously used and covered in doodles?</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>Purchase the basic supplies children of various ages need. The supplies would then be divided into individual containers and age specific boxes would be given to each of the schools for distribution to the children who need it most. I plan on making at least 50 boxes, possibly more if I can procure more community donations. I hope to eventually make this project an ongoing effort so that all children can have new school supplies each year.</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-14</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-14</date_updated>
    <location_postal>65708</location_postal>
    <location_lat>36.870610</location_lat>
    <location_long>-93.845173</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>0</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>3</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/fresh-start-supplies</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>Project Linus</title>
    <essay_see_it>Project Linus&#039; mission is to provide love, a sense of security, warmth and comfort to children who are seriously ill, traumatized, or otherwise in need through the gifts of new, handmade blankets and afghans, lovingly created by volunteer &quot;blanketeers.&quot; The problem is sad kids. We don&#039;t want sad kids.</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>Those children have been in horrible environments. We as individuals in a club are given so many opportunities to do whatever, so we feel like we should help. We would like to cheer up at least a few children.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>We bought cloth and fabric using our club expenses and borrowed scissors from our school&#039;s art department. We made 1 blanket a month for 4 months from December through March. Then we dropped them off at our local Project Linus Chapter.</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-14</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-14</date_updated>
    <location_postal>50010</location_postal>
    <location_lat>42.041626</location_lat>
    <location_long>-93.601521</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>4</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>15</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/project-linus-1</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>Preparing for Disaster in Atlantic County, NJ</title>
    <essay_see_it>Here at the Atlantic County Institute of Technology, we are committed to disaster preparedness for our local community and the entire nation.  When disasters happen, relief workers and emergency services teams arrive on the scene quickly, but cannot always reach everyone immediately.  On top of that, people who need to evacuate their homes will often leave many possessions behind, and may be forced to live in shelters for weeks at a time.  We are hoping to make this process just a little bit easier on those in need.</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>As a previous grantee from Learn and Serve America, we became involved in disaster preparedness activities, and learned some truly surprising things.  According to government statistics, over 800,000 people in the US each year are affected by natural disasters.  Even more impactful for us was the fact that those in coastal communities are often the most vulnerable to such incidents (our student body is largely from Atlantic City, NJ).  We want to help make a difference for vulnerable communities before disasters strike, so they can get on with their lives afterwards.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>We hope to make disaster preparedness kits for distribution in local communities vulnerable to natural disasters.  We will be stuffing backpacks with various items that will be useful for youth who have been forced to evacuate their homes, including: notebooks/journals, pens and pencils, books, crayons/drawing paper for younger children, and whatever we can find that may make life in an evacuation shelter more amenable.</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-14</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-14</date_updated>
    <location_postal>08330</location_postal>
    <location_lat>39.482095</location_lat>
    <location_long>-74.757115</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>25</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>50</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/preparing-disaster-atlantic-county-nj</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>Brush With Kindess</title>
    <essay_see_it>During the recent Oklahoma storms, hundreds of homes were damaged.  Some homes belonged to low-income families who had can not afford insurance, much less repairs to the house.  Brush With Kindness</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>Low-income people need a healthy and safe home.  Its proven that children who live in poor housing conditions increase the risk of severe ill-health or disability by up to 25% during childhood and early adulthood.  The biggest problem in Oklahoma is pest infestation.  Can you imagine not being able to sleep because cockroaches are in your sheets?</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>&quot;A Brush With Kindess&quot; is a program about repairing houses, one at a time through simple acts of kindness.  Central Oklahoma Habitat will identify those low-income homeowners who have had storm damage, recruit volunteers, and work with the homeowner to make their house habitable once again.  To date, we have completed over 30 homes in the Oklahoma City metro area.</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-14</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-14</date_updated>
    <location_postal>73127</location_postal>
    <location_lat>35.470996</location_lat>
    <location_long>-97.649386</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>35</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>500</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/brush-kindess</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>Reach for Single Mothers</title>
    <essay_see_it>Reach&#039;s main objective is to eliminate all natures of the poverty mindset and with eliminating this we, then know, that we could eliminate all aspects of violence, drugs usage/selling, emotional toll, teen pregnancies, etc. So what Reach does is that we research every negative thing that derives from the poverty mindset and we do our best to eliminate it. One of those things are growing up in a fatherless home. Based on our research we learned that compared to peers in two-parent homes, black children in single-parent households are more likely to engage in troublesome behavior, and perform poorly in school and Kids living in single-parent homes or in step-families report lower educational expectations on the part of their parents, less parental monitoring of school work, and less overall social supervision than children from intact families. There are many more statistics but these are ones that Reach plans to eliminate altogether.</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>Personally, growing up with only my mom raising me and my two older brothers on our own without any help from my father it caused anger and pure envy for most of my friends who grew up with a father in their house or at least a father figure. My mom raised us while trying to still secure our future and her dream of being a lawyer. She ended up going to law school and graduating from Rutgers without any help from my father. The emotional toll behind this and the loneliness of believing that there we were the only children who had to grow up without a father in the house caused personality traits that still linger on us to this day. I want this feeling to be nonexistent for other fatherless children.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>First, to gather up people who I can trust and who will be dedicated to the cause. Then, I will have to have begin organizing the performers and the venue and getting the word out there to different people all over the city of Philadelphia. I would have people volunteer a single mother who deserves whatever surprise we could have for them such as donating about 100 dollars to them or sending their family on a cruise or something beneficial to them. We would decide on the winner based on who believe needs it the most and deserves it the most.</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-13</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-13</date_updated>
    <location_postal>19012</location_postal>
    <location_lat>40.059505</location_lat>
    <location_long>-75.104914</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>80</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>30</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/reach-single-mothers</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>Relay for Life: Pelham 2011</title>
    <essay_see_it>We participated in the 2nd annual Relay for Life Event.  We walked around the track from 6pm to 6am to show that cancer never sleeps.  We are raising money to bring about new cancer research to help cancer patients celebrate more birthdays.</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>Relay for Life is important to me because I know many people who have been touched by cancer.  It is nice to know that we are supporting them.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>I recruited a team of members to support Reach Out to Jean&#039;s Team at Relay for Life.  They individually had to raise $100 each and as a group we raised over $3,000.  We hosted a bake sale, sold cancer bracelets, held a cake walk, hired a professional masseuse to help fundraise, and held a raffle.  We also had carnival games at our event to fundraise money for Relay for Life.</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-13</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-13</date_updated>
    <location_postal>10803</location_postal>
    <location_lat>40.900493</location_lat>
    <location_long>-73.809557</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>1000</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>20</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/relay-life-pelham-2011</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>Clothing Drive</title>
    <essay_see_it>We tried to help people, especially children, who lead lives of poverty or are in need of clothes.</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>This is important to us because we are looking to help as many people as we can in even the smallest ways. We wanted to help those in need by giving them the opportunity to purchase clothes that are still in good condition at a lower price.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>First, we went to our school principle to obtain permission to host the clothing drive in our school.  Next, all six of us made posters, flyers, and announcements to get the word out about the clothing drive.  We also brought in boxes for the clothes. Then, each day after school we brought home the clothes people donated because the boxes were full.  Finally, we brought all the clothes together and drove to the Goodwill nearest us to donate the clothes. About 40 bags of clothes were donated, and we needed three vans to deliver all the bags of clothes to Goodwill.</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-13</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-13</date_updated>
    <location_postal>18020</location_postal>
    <location_lat>40.670282</location_lat>
    <location_long>-75.329557</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>200</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>21</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/clothing-drive-3</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>2012 BMW Championship</title>
    <essay_see_it>https://events.trustevent.com/styles/T000007/index.cfm?eid=687#</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>2012 BMW Championship

It is important for people to get involved with such a great tournament/event that is happening in their community.  A lot of help is needed to run such a big event.  The great part about tournaments such as the BMW is that a large portion of help comes from the surrounding community, giving everybody a chance to participate in making it a great event.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>Recruit people to help out the 2012 BMW Championship</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-13</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-13</date_updated>
    <location_postal>46032</location_postal>
    <location_lat>39.969300</location_lat>
    <location_long>-86.165002</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>70</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>2600</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/2012-bmw-championship-1</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>2012 BMW Championship</title>
    <essay_see_it>https://events.trustevent.com/styles/T000007/index.cfm?eid=687#</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>2012 BMW Championship

It is important for people to get involved with such a great tournament/event that is happening in their community.  A lot of help is needed to run such a big event.  The great part about tournaments such as the BMW is that a large portion of help comes from the surrounding community, giving everybody a chance to participate in making it a great event.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>Recruit people to help out the 2012 BMW Championship</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-13</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-13</date_updated>
    <location_postal>46032</location_postal>
    <location_lat>39.969300</location_lat>
    <location_long>-86.165002</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>70</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>2600</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/2012-bmw-championship-0</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <title>2012 BMW Championship</title>
    <essay_see_it>https://events.trustevent.com/styles/T000007/index.cfm?eid=687#</essay_see_it>
    <essay_believe_it>2012 BMW Championship

It is important for people to get involved with such a great tournament/event that is happening in their community.  A lot of help is needed to run such a big event.  The great part about tournaments such as the BMW is that a large portion of help comes from the surrounding community, giving everybody a chance to participate in making it a great event.</essay_believe_it>
    <essay_build_it>Recruit people to help out the 2012 BMW Championship</essay_build_it>
    <essay_next_steps></essay_next_steps>
    <date_created>2011-06-13</date_created>
    <date_updated>2011-06-13</date_updated>
    <location_postal>46032</location_postal>
    <location_lat>39.969300</location_lat>
    <location_long>-86.165002</location_long>
    <num_people_impacted>70</num_people_impacted>
    <num_people_involved>2600</num_people_involved>
    <Path>http://www.dosomething.org/project/2012-bmw-championship</Path>
  </node>
</xml>

